twinity.com 2019-05-15

# Twinity - Privacy Policy

We want you to know that you can trust us with your personal data. Which is why we would like to tell you about our privacy policy for handling your data. Rest assured that we also comply with all relevant data protection laws.

### At Twinity, you decide!

Our most important rule at Twinity is: If you choose not to disclose information to the public or to selected members of the Twinity community yourself, we will not do so either. There is only one exception to this rule: When we are required to do so by law, especially upon court or administrative order.

### How do we collect, process, and store personal data?

We only collect the personal data you submit to us yourself, with very few exceptions relating to usage data, which are explained in detail below. We require you to submit some mandatory data; other data can be disclosed as a matter of choice.

### Mandatory information

You will be required to submit some personal information as well as in the case of a Commercial Membership some company information (herinafter: ìrequired informationî) in order to be able to use Twinity. The following mandatory information is automatically disclosed to all other members:

  * Your gender
  * Your display name (either your first name or your first and last names)

We will display your first name only by default. You also have the option of switching to displaying your first and last names.

If you are a Commercial Member the following additional mandatory company information is automatically disclosed to all other members:

  * Company Name
  * Company Website

### Optional information

In addition to the information you submitted when registering, you are free to submit further information (hereinafter “optional information”), which helps other Twinity members learn more about you, and your interests and preferences. If you submit optional information, it is accessible to all other Twinity members unless otherwise specified. If you no longer wish other members to see this optional information, you can delete this information at any time.

### Your friends, places, events, and items

Twinity allows other members to see all your optional information, as well as lists of your friends, places, events, and items by default.

### A word of warning

Please remember that any information you disclose to all or selected members of the Twinity community is public. Even if you disclose information to selected persons only, you can never be sure what they will do with it. So please think twice about the possible consequences before disclosing data to anyone. The only thing we can promise is that we do not use your data for any other purpose.

### Personal statistics

The personal statistics about you that are listed in your profile are always visible to all Twinity members. These include the following:

  * Your date of registration
  * Your number of friends
  * Your number of places, events, and items
  * Your type of membership

### What is usage data?

Whenever you use Twinity, we store the domain name and/or IP address of the computer that contacts us, as well as the data request of the client (file name and URL), http response code, referring website, date and duration of your visit, and the requested pages of our website. Furthermore, some of your actions (e.g. performing an animation, uploading an object, etc.) will be logged when you use the client. These actions are logged anonymously. We store this kind of usage data to track malfunctions and abuse of Twinity and our services. It may also be required for establishing subsequent connections or for payment purposes. We also use it to improve our services.

### What happens to my personal data?

Metaversum may pass on payment data to service providers or third parties insofar as this is required for billing. Metaversum will disclose the names of these third parties. Inasmuch as we use personal data to build user profiles, we will not disclose these profiles to anyone without your prior consent. However, we may enable third parties to communicate with you through us for advertising purposes. Unless you expressly instruct us otherwise, your profile might be used to select advertising information that matches your interests, based on the information you submit, as well as your activity in Twinity. Third parties may only communicate with you through us, which means that we do not disclose your usage data to third parties. When we analyze statistical data, we disclose this analysis to third parties in anonymous form only. Inasmuch as we work together with third parties to deliver our services to you (e.g. hosting, call centers, etc.) and they receive personal data, we will oblige them to respect the relevant data protection laws and ensure sufficient data protection.

### What is a cookie?

A cookie is a small file that is sent from a web server to a userís computer when they visit a website. It is stored on the computerís hard drive. If the same web server is visited again, the web browser sends the cookie back to the server. The server can then process the information contained therein. Cookies are used to facilitate navigation on a website (which might ërememberí information that was previously submitted), or to manage advertising banners (so you do not see the same banner over and over again). Cookies have an expiry date, after which they automatically end. You are free to delete cookies from your hard drive manually or deactivate cookies completely via your browser settings. Twinity does not use cookies for personal data, but only to see when was the last time you visited us.

### What is an IP address?

IP addresses allow devices that are connected to the internet to be identified. Every computer that is connected to the internet has its own IP address, which is a unique combination of numbers. Your internet provider is able to identify you via your IP address.

### What should I know about changing or deleting my personal data?

We aim to store correct and up-to-date personal data. You can change your data (i.e. update, rectify, or amend it) or delete it. To protect your privacy and for your own security, we check your identity before you can do so. To change your account data or if you no longer want us to use your account data, please contact us at [twhelp@twinity.com](mailto:twhelp@twinity.com). In the latter case we will delete your data as soon as possible. However, please note that due to technical and organizational reasons, some measures that have already commenced may be completed even after receipt of your email. We reserve the right to modify this privacy policy from time to time at our own discretion and always respecting the relevant data protection laws. We will inform you if we intend to extend the scope with which your personal data is used.

Last modified: 23 July 2008

### Archived:

  * 11 December 2007
